# Xiling Li

Tel: 206-228-1052 Email: xiling.li@northwestern.edu Location: Evanston, IL, USA Personal Website: https://xilinggrantli.github.io Google Scholar DBLP

RESEARCH INTERESTS Broadly speaking, my research focuses on security, privacy and trustworthiness of data management and applications including verifiable query evaluation (DB) and privacy-preserving machine learning (PPML), and works extensively with secure multiparty computation, zero-knowledge proof and differential privacy.

**EDUCATION** 

Ph.D. Computer Science, Northwestern University

Jun 2021 - Present

• Advisor: Dr. Jennie Rogers

M.S. Computer Science, University of Washington

Dec 2020

• Advisor: Dr. Martine De Cock

• Thesis: Privacy-Preserving Filter-based Feature Selection with Secure Multiparty Computation

**B.S. Computer Science**, University of California, San Diego

Dec 2016

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

## Research Assistant, Northwestern University

Jun 2021 - Present

- <u>ZKSQL</u> (VLDB 2023): Proposed the first work [2] on verifiable and efficient query evaluation with zero knowledge proofs for ad-hoc SQL queries in an operator-at-a-time fashion.
- <u>RESCU-SQL</u> (VLDB 2023 demo): Proposed the first pragmatic OLAP system [1] with all-but-one malicious security for ad-hoc SQL queries.

Research Assistant, University of Washington @PPML Group

Sep 2019 - May 2021

- UbiTtention 2020 Workshop (UbiComp-ISWC 2020): Proposed Mean-Split Gini Impurity algorithm (MS-GINI) [4] for Filter-based Feature Selection (FFS).
- ICML 2021: Proposed the first general FFS-based secure multiparty computation protocol [3] with active security and honest majority, and instantiated feature scoring protocol based on MS-GINI.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

#### **Guest Lecturer**

- Database Architecture and Query Evaluation, COMP\_SCI 339, Northwestern University
  Fall 2023
- Relational Algebra, COMP\_SCI 339, Northwestern University

Spring 2024

**Teaching Assistant** 

• COMP\_SCI 339: Intro to Database Systems, Northwestern University

Spring 2023

• COMP\_SCI 339: Intro to Database Systems, Northwestern University

Spring 2024

INDUSTRIAL EXPERIENCE

### Data Scientist, IBM @Watson IoT

Jan 2018 - Aug 2019

- Developed a case-based reasoning system for disaster prevention based on knowledge graph.
  - Developed a defective product detection vision system based on object detection of different crucial parts of product and defective classification according to partial detection of the product.
  - Developed a real-time multi-face recognition system for storage monitoring.

Android Developer, Shenzhen Das Intellitech Co.,Ltd @R&D Department

Jul 2017 - Dec 2017

• Developed Android app as the client side of intelligent building systems

**SERVICES** 

Reviewer: ICML 2021, 2022, 2023, 2024; NeurIPS 2021, 2022, 2023, 2024; ICLR 2022, 2023, 2024

Invited

**Privacy + Machine Learning**, Northwestern AI Journal Club, Nov 2021.

TALKS

TECHNICAL C++, Python, Java, EMP-toolkit, Scikit-Learn, PyTorch, MP-SPDZ, AWS EC2, Ubuntu, Docker

SKILLS

OPEN SOURCE ARTIFACTS **Xiling Li**, Chenkai Weng, Yongxin Xu, Xiao Wang, Jennie Rogers. *ZKSQL: Verifiable and Efficient Query Evaluation with Zero-Knowledge Proofs*. https://github.com/vaultdb/zksql, Feb 2023.

# SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

- [1] Xiling Li\*, Gefei Tan\*, Xiao Wang, Jennie Rogers, Soamar Homsi. *RESCU-SQL: Oblivious Querying for the Zero Trust Cloud.* In Proceedings of the VLDB Endowment (PVLDB), Volume 16, No. 12, 4086-4089, 2023. DOI:https://doi.org/ 10.14778/3611540.3611627.
- [2] **Xiling Li**, Chenkai Weng, Yongxin Xu, Xiao Wang, Jennie Rogers. *ZKSQL: Verifiable and Efficient Query Evaluation with Zero-Knowledge Proofs*. In Proceedings of the VLDB Endowment (PVLDB), Volume 16, No. 8, 1804-1816, 2023. DOI:https://doi.org/10.14778/3594512.3594513.
- [3] **Xiling Li**, Rafael Dowsley, Martine De Cock. *Privacy-Preserving Feature Selection with Secure Multiparty Computation*, In Proceedings of the 38th International Conference on Machine Learning, PMLR 139:6326-6336, 2021.
- [4] **Xiling Li**, Martine De Cock. *Cognitive load detection from wrist-band sensors*. In Adjunct Proceedings of the 2020 ACM International Joint Conference on Pervasive and Ubiquitous Computing and Proceedings of the 2020 ACM International Symposium on Wearable Computers (UbiComp-ISWC '20). ACM, New York, NY, USA, 456–461. DOI: https://doi.org/10.1145/3410530.3414428